<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<information>
  <features>
    <feature value="soul">
      <description>
The first number is the day of birth. This is your Soul Number. Day of birth is
equal to Soul. For example, if your birthday is September 12nd, then your Soul
Number is 1 + 2 = 3.

Note: a number lower than 12 is not added!

This number is your particular spiritual body which represents your link to your
Soul. 1f you work at it and master this energy, then under stress you will be
able to automatically communicate with your soul. Stress is always involved with
the Soul Body; it is one of the biggest things that you must overcome in your
life.

Abandonement is the bottom line of all the psychological traumas you have ever
had. The feeling of abandonement is the biggest mountain that you have to climb,
otherwise your Soul would not be important. Soul is your only friend.

The Soul is defined as Deep Inner Peace - you can go inside yourself and it is
totally peaceful. Karma is external, Soul is internal. Peace is the quest of
both of them - a harmony.

The Soul is normally the weak link that keeps you from finding your true self.

Your Soul Body is your creative energy, it the Creator in you. It is the
conflict between the heart and the head. The key is to come from the heart. Let
the heart rule the head. Don’t forget the head, just let the heart rule it.
      </description>
    </feature>
    <feature value="karma">
      <description>
The month is the Karma Number. 1f you were born in December, then your Karma
Number is: 1 + 2 = 3.

Note: a number lower than 12 is not added!

Most people are stuck with their Karma, but when they begin a spiritual
discipline the karma is taken care of. “Where there’s Dharma there's no karma.”

What is Karma? Karma is the outward conflict with the world. It is your external
harmony.

Most of us got involved with 3H0 by the Grace of God. Our world was falling
apart and all of a sudden we started doing a little Kundalini Yoga, then
everything got to be a little smoother, and as we went along our chanting got
better and everything else seemed to be going better for us. Our bodies were in
horrible shape; we were seeking shelter from the pressures of the external
world. With discipline our nervous systems got stronger and more
harrnonious. When Yogi Bhajan says, “Where there is Dharma there’s no karma,” he
means that our external worlds get harmonized.

After about 3 years of doing Kundalini Yoga you realize, “Ha, it is not the
external world that’s freaking me out, it’s my internal reality that’s freaking
me out.” Then this is when you begin to fight Shakti Pad.

When you conquer Shakti Pad you find your soul. In order to find your soul you
must get rid of fear. The main thing that blocks us all is fear. The fear of
what?

Each one of us has a different spiritual body that doesn’t work. When we get
fearful, the fear comes from the spiritual body that is not working. When that
spiritual body starts working, the fear will be gone.
      </description>
    </feature>
    <feature value="gift">
      <description>
The last two digits of the year you were bom in is the third number. For
example, if you were born in 1950, the Year Number is the digits 5 + 0. Add only
the last two digits of the year. Because for the year 99 (9+9=18=1+8=9) the gift
is 9 , is in the year 00 the gift 10. This number represents God’s Gift to you
in this lifetime. It means that this particular spiritual body was a gift to
you.

Note: a number lower than 12 is not added!

The Gift Number is what it says - God’s gift to you. He has given you that
particular spiritual body; it works really well for you. It’s something that you
can rely on; it’s your basis for strength.

When I do the numbers for people I often ask the question, “Did you have a hard
time accepting gifts when you were young?” There have been 3 or 4 cases where
people have refused to use their Gift in this lifetime. Yogi Bhajan has been
extremely heavy with those people because they were refusing the one thing that
God gave them directly. A lot of people have a hard time accepting gifts and
they don’ t recognize the fact that they have the power of that particular Gift
Number; they are not using it; they have no strength that they can fall back on.

A lot of people who arent’t doing any spiritual discipline don’t use their Gift
at all - they don’t know what they’re doing, they don’t have their
strength. These people don’t use anything as their strength.

People who are not spiritual are self-destructive; we all know that. When we
weren’ t spiritual we were doing all kinds of things to self-destruct. The
minute we begin to look at things positively, when we feel that there is hope,
we begin to use our Gift. When we begin to use our Gift, we begin to express
ourselves positively.

As long as you accept your Gift you have the ability to tune in to your
Soul. What that means is that you can go right to a peaceful place when you are
under stress, you have the ability to connect with your Soul at that particular
time.
      </description>
    </feature>
    <feature value="destiny">
      <description>
The fourth number is called the Century Number, and in the example of the year
1950 it is the addition of 1 + 9 + 5 + 0. The Destiny Number is also defined as
how people see you in society, how you come off to people.

As another example, a birth in the year 1955 will have a Century Number of 1 + 9
+ 5 + 5, which is equal to 20, and 2 + 0 = 2, that is, the Century Number for
1955 is 2.

Note: a number lower than 12 is not added!

The Destiny Number is the number which represents what you have done for many
life times before, what you have worked on for many lifetimes. It can be good or
bad; it depends on the chart. Most of the time it is something you worked on for
many lifetimes and it is a quality or a talent that you have. It is what people
see in you, and it is something you can rely on and use to help you.

Year and Century Numbers seem to be positive with people who are on a spiritual
path.
      </description>
    </feature>
    <feature value="path">
      <description>
The Path Number is the fifth number. This is your Fulfillment Number - what you
have to do in this lifetime to feel fulfilled - what you have to do in order to
be divine. The Path Number is also called Destiny Number.

The way you calculate the Path Nurnber is as follows: Day + Month + Century =
Path Number

For example, if your birthday is September 2, 1950, your Path Nurnber is: 2 + 9
+ 1 + 9 + 5 + 0 = 26 = 2 + 6 = 8

Your Path Number is the addition of your entire birthdate.

Note: a number lower than 12 is not added!

Path is Fulfillment. You can go sit in a cave and find your soul, but
fulfillment is found when you become divine. When you master this number you
really feel like you are doing what you are supposed to do - why you came to
this earth level.

Each of the ten Sikh Gurus mastered a certain quality. (See Description of the
ten bodies). These qualities were the examples of their lives. We can use these
qualities as touchstones in terms of the Path Number. These qualities are the
level of evolvement that one’s path has to reach; This is the mode of
transmitting one’s spiritual energy when one has achieved inner peace.

There are several States of consciousness called Pads. After Shakti Pad comes
Sahaj Pad. In this state you become divine. When you lose your fear you become
divine. When you feel divine you are fulfilled. When you master the spiritual
body represented by the Path Number your divinity begins to radiate.
      </description>
    </feature>
  </features>
  <numbers>
    <number value="1">
      <description>
The first Spiritual Body is the Soul: it is represented by Guru Nanak and Guru
Nanak represented Humility.  The negative aspect of the number 1 is
non-creativity. A person with a 1 in a negative position will have zero
creativity. This is the most negative aspect of the number 1. He will be
completely head-dominant.
      </description>
      <karma>
A person who has a 1 in the Karma position normally relates to other people from
the head. In order to be happy in the external realm, this person has to come
from his heart, and the people that he deals with have to feel that he is coming
from the heart; this is crucial for him if he wants to have harmony in his
external world.

Any particular technique that will work on harmonizing the 1 will also allow a
person who has a 1 in the Karma position to feel in harmony with all his
external dealings.
      </karma>
      <soul>
A person with a 1 in the Soul position is the kind of person who in his internal
relationship with himself will create a circular argument with his subconscious
and get stuck there. His tendency will be to deal with his internal stress from
his head. This is frustating to him because his logic will carry him to a dead
end and he will not be able to get out of that stress.

If these people do a meditation or some sort of practice that will give them
control of the first spiritual body then they will find that their logic will be
conquered; they will begin to come from their heart and they will know what is
right even if it doesn’t make logical sense. Their internal peace will come into
harmony because they will be able to come from their hearts.
      </soul>
      <gift>
A person with a Gift of 1, like someone born in 1901, will have the ability to
come from his heart as long as he is on a spiritual path. One’s Gift works when
a person makes a committment to follow some spiritual path.

The number 1 represents “creativity”, so creativity is the real key. A person
who has a 1 as a Gift will be super-creative.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
In terms of Destiny a 1 means that this person has been very creative in many
lifetimes before. If a person is on a spiritual path he will appear very
creative to people who observe him from the outside.
      </destiny>
      <path>
A person with a Path of 1 has to be very creative in order to feel really deeply
fulfilled and to feel like he did his mission for God on this earth. Guru Nanak
was in this position, his Destiny represents this number 1 - he created Sikh
Dharma. A person who has a 1 in his Path would be in this same situation - his
spirituality would be expressed through this creativity of God.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="2">
      <description>
The key phrase for the number 2 is “Longing to Belong.” In order to make this
number harmonize you have to connect with your spiritual teacher. This body is
represented by Guru Angad - Obedience.

The negative aspect of the number 2 is that this person will form negative
associations or he will be unable to calculate the danger in any situation.
      </description>
      <karma>
In the birthday of february 13th, 1954, the formula gives a 4 as Soul number, a
2 as Karma Number, a 9 as gift and a 10 as destiny:

In order for this person to be in tune with his Karma (2), to make sure that his
external world is going right- his Negative Mind has to work. Karmically, this
person would be very susceptible to try to connect with everyone. He would try
to connect no matter what. He needs the company of quality people (The Company
of the Holy) in order to be of quality himself. If his Negative Mind works he
can calculate the danger in any relationship and he would make sure that the
relationship would be beneficial to his Soul. When he is stressed out he might
not be able to be neutral about the situation that he is in. In order to be in
tune with his Soul, which is the number 4, it is important for this person to
master the Neutral Mind so that whenever he is forced into a stressful situation
his yogic mind will automatically calculate the correct action; this is called
intuition.

In a business sense, this person does business to make a friend, to make a
connection, or to form a close tie with somebody. This person may make a deal
where he would lose money in order to gain a friend. Thus, in a negative sense,
this person is easily taken advantage of in business dealings as well as
emotional relationships.
      </karma>
      <soul>
The key for a person with a 2 in the Soul position is to process his longing to
the point of neutrality. This person asks himself, “What can I learn from this
relationship or this situation?” If this number is working for the person, the
first thing he remembers is that he is connected to God, then he makes a neutral
evaluation of the situation to see if there is anything that could affect his
soul in a negative way. He makes a roadmap through meditational processes and
connects with his spiritual teacher. Connecting to his spiritual teacher he is
connected to God, therefore, his connection to people is not that important.

Protecting oneself is basically what this number is about, protecting one’s own
spirituality and one’s own soul.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person has the ability to connect to anyone and to make everyone feel
relaxed. A Gift of 2 means one has the ability to calculate the danger in any
situation and this is valuable when one has to make a very accurate evaluation
of the danger.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
If a person with a Destiny of 2 has made the choice to be spiritual, people will
look at this person as being an easy person to talk to, an easy person to
connect with, someone who has a level head about relationships, a friend.
      </destiny>
      <path>
The number 2 is represented by Guru Arnad. He represents the perfect student and
super-obedience. He was the one who walked miles to the river to bring water to
the guru - total dedication, total connectedness to the Infinity of the Guru.

A person with a Path of 2 has to show this deep connection to Infinity. I look
at it in terms of devotion, how a person should enact devotion towards
Infinity. A number here teaches devotion.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="3">
      <description>
The Third Spiritual Body is the Positive Mind. It is represented by Guru Amar
Das - Equality.

A 3 is flexible and mischievous. He gets pulled down by negativity and needs a
positive sense of humor.  The negative aspect of the number 3 is that this
person will not able to see the good in situations.
      </description>
      <karma>
The Karma for this person is to be positive in terms of his external
relationships. In a business situation you will see that this person cannot make
it because everything about the business world is negative. After a little bit
of stress he can’t handle the relationship because his mind won’t focus on the
positive; his mind is always focusing on the negative aspects. He is stuck in
the Negative Mind.

To harmonize his Karma he needs to do a meditation, a yoga set or some practice,
for 1000 days to hope to see a little bit of light at the end of the tunnel. He
needs to see the harmony and the goodness in his work situation; then his mind
will focus on the positive aspect of the relationship.
      </karma>
      <soul>
This position is the internal process of how one deals with himself. Let’s say
he has an argument with somebody; after he works through it he will say:‘You
know, all this is happening because I am such a creep, I am just no
good. . .“. In other words, this person’s own internal process will be to negate
himself - a sort of an inferiority complex - not being able to see himself
clearly in a positive light.

This person has to see himself as a Soul, as being part of God, instead of
seeing himself as a sinner and as part of the Devil.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person will always have a positive thing to say. Evervbody else can be
negative but he will listen to them and it will not be a problem. He will say,
“But have you ever looked at it from this point of view...". This is his
Gift. He always has a cheery attitude about things.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
People will see somebody who has a Destiny of 3 as a cheerful person, as
somebody who always has a positive input. Let’s say that I am a businessman and
I want to hire a salesman. I might be able to look at this persons numbers and
say, “He appears to be pretty happy but he has 3 as his Destiny.” I would say to
him, “I’d like to observe you for a week”. In reality I may observe that this
person really does have a very cheerful, positive outlook and I will feel that
this will be beneficial to me as the employer.
      </destiny>
      <path>
Three is Equality; this was the great quality of Guru Amar Das. In order to see
Guru Amar Das, first you had to sit in langar and eat, even if you were the
king. He realized that all people were equal; he created free kitchens; he
wanted to make sure that everyone was taken care of.

A person who has this quality will want to see equality in all situations, he
wants to take care of everyone and is concerned about everyone.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="4">
      <description>
The Fourth Body is the Neutral Mind. It is represented by Guru Ram Das - Service.
      </description>
      <karma>
In the negative sense, this person has the inability to be neutral; he has an
opinion or a comment about everything. He is the most opinionated person in the
world; he loves to argue whether he’s right or wrong, or whether it has been
proven right or wrong; it doesn’t matter to him, he just has to comment on
everything.

By doing a practice or a meditation this person can hope to accomplish
neutrality. He will gain the ability to listen and to make a neutral decision
about the process he is involved in. A 4 in a positive sense is a listener and a
source of blessings.
      </karma>
      <soul>
This person is very indecisive. He will say, “Well, I don’t know; I’m not sure;
let me think about it..." He is never able to make a decision because he can’ t
come to that point of neutrality. If he has the positive quality of this number
he will be very decisive; he will be able to very quickly analyze himself. He
may know himself so quickly that he will know the accurate answer
immediately. He can listen to his own inner voice and he is totally sure; he is
a yogi in terms of his Soul.
      </soul>
      <gift>
A Gift of 4 means that this person has a Yogic Mind. This person is neutral,
humble, and loves to be serviceful.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
People will see this person as being neutral. People come to this person for
advise.
      </destiny>
      <path>
This number represents Service. This person has to become very serviceful
oriented. Guru Ram Das has given the exarnple of building the Temple over and
over and over again, seven times. This is what this person must strive for -
humility and servicefulness. If this person does his meditation or sings Guru
Ram Das’ shabads for 1000 days, he will be in tune with what it takes to express
his own divinity.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="5">
      <description>
The 5th Body is the Physical Body and physical things are pretty easy for
someone with a 5 in his numbers. It is easy for a person with a 5 to push
himself physically. He has a strong body and has the ability to sacrifice. Use
what you have to overcome your weaknesses.

The Fifth Body is represented by Guru Arjun. It represents the Physical Body but
it is also the Teacher number. Guru Arjun had so much physical control that he
sat on the hot plate and chanted Wahe Guru. That was his example. Guru Arjun
represents Self-sacrifice.

The negative aspect of the number 5 is that these people have a lot of problems
with their physical body. They can’t control their physicial environment at all
- it is hard for them to do exercises and it is hard for them to keep control of
their weight. They love to eat and they can become lazy. They prefer comfort
over sacrifice. They are scared to death to teach.

A 5 is half God and half Man (half balance).      
      </description>
      <karma>
The negative aspect of the Fifth Spiritual Body in the Karma position is
manifested in somebody who is self-indulgent and extremely overweight. In a
business situation this person is seen as being self-interested and
self-motivated. After mastery of this body this person will be able to make
sacrifices and will have the willpower to make certain things happen in his
relationships.
      </karma>
      <soul>
The key word here is Balance. A person with this body out of tune cannot reach a
balance in his internal processes. Rather than going to Solstice he stays home
in his nice, cozy house because he can’t make that sacrifice for his own
spiritual growth. He can’t push himself out in front of a class to teach about
God because he hasn’t reached that comfortable place within himself. The block
to finding his own Soul is that he doesn’t have the ability to sit down and do a
meditation for 1000 days. He doesn’t have the ability to do an exercise set to
get rid of his obesity or whatever health problem he may be having. His
self-indulgence takes him down the path of self-distruction; whereas a person
who goes through a clearing process for 1000 days and gets in charge of the
Fifth Spiritual Body will have the ability to sacrifice his own comfort so he
can be less angry.
      </soul>
      <gift>
The number 5 is my Gift: The ability to teach. It has always been easy for me to
teach. As soon as I was in 3HO I was teaching. Teaching has never been a problem
for me; it is like eating breakfast - there is no hassle to it, in fact, it is
quite enjoyable and a very pleasurable experience. I have always enjoyed helping
others learn. To discipline my physical body bas never been hard either.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
This person will be seen as the personification of God which is what Guru Arjun
represented. He will be seen as someone who can make self-sacrifices.
      </destiny>
      <path>
This person must become a teacher by example. This is what Guru Arjun
represented - teaching by example. People need to see that this person lives his
example and that he is the personification of what he teaches.

By doing a particular discipline for l000 day's this person can tune himself to
the fact that he has to live what he is teaching. In the present lifetime this
person must teach to feel divine.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="6">
      <description>
The Arc Line is the Sixth Spiritual Body and the Sixth Guru was the master of
the Arc Line. His actions, his life, his entire purpose, was to teach us about
the Arc Line. Guru Hargobind stands for Justice.

A person with a 6 will love to meditate. A “Person at Prayer” is someone who
really likes to meditate. It should be easy for someone in 3H0 to meditate, so a
person with a 6 will benefit from meditation. Other people have other talents -
it may be counseling, it may be physical yoga sets, it may be music.

The number 6 represents the Are Line, and the strength of this body will depend
on whether the person has a 6 as his Soul Number or his Gift Number. It depends
on how much he has worked on himself and it depends on his ability to
meditate. It is going to depend on the person - if he is doing nothing spiritual
the 6 may not work at all, then the Arc Line will be his biggest block. But if
he worked on himself for 1000 days developing himself with meditation, his Are
Line will be his biggest asset.

The Are Line gives you your intuitive ability. The negative aspect of the number
6 is that this person will be non-intuitive, he will talk without thinking and
will have a hard time in situations where he has to concentrate.
      </description>
      <karma>
The person who doesn’t have control of the Sixth Body in the Karma position will
not have the power of the word in his business and personal relationships. He
will say something but he won’t be able to live up to that because he doesn’t
have the power of the word. He will not be constant for consistent. What a
person can hope to gain through mastering this position will be the ability to
be consistent, to follow through, to meet his commitments, to be one-pointed and
very concentrated.
      </karma>
      <soul>
If a person’s Soul number is 6, then when he is onder stress his key is to keep
his center. What is the center? It is the Soul, the sense of “self”, it is “who”
one is. When one is under stress one should have his Are Line working for
him. If one is under stress and his Are Line doesn’t work, this block will not
allow him to tune in into the deeper levels of himself.

If this person’s Arc Line doesn’t work, the information that he interprets will
be contradictory; he is always in a state of confusion about what is going
on. Doing a meditation or a process for 1000 days will give him the ability to
be very confident and be sure that he knows exactly what is going on.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person is totally one-pointed about everything that he does.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
The number 6 is “Person at Prayer.” It is the Arc Line. I have a 6 as my Destiny
Number and for some reason my Arc Line has always worked; I always loved to
meditate. I used the 5 and the 6 as my talents to work on the other bodies. In
other words, meditation seemed to be the most natural way for me to work through
my Karma, Soul and Path.

Other people will see a person with a Destiny of 6 as being one-pointed and very
prayerful.
      </destiny>
      <path>
The negative aspect of this position is that this person will not want to be a
“person at prayer” ; he won’ t even consider it. People don’t usually consider
their Path until they have found their Soul.

This person’ s divine expression as a human being is to be a channel that people
relate to as a person at prayer - a holy person, a representative of God - very
prayerful, very meditative, very concentrated doing whatever it is that he does.

As an example, let’s say this person is a lawyer. People need to see him having
total control in a courtroom situation - he is never thrown off by anything that
comes along in court; he always maintains a prayerful, calm, and confident
poise.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="7">
      <description>
The Seventh Body is the Aura. The number 7 is what gives the person the ability
to uplift, what makes a person feel at peace. It is Mercy.

The number 7 has tremendous qualities. The number 7 will want to be up-front; he
will do this because he wants to elevate people. A 7 may be a singer (singing
can open people’s heart), he can heal with his voice, or he might want to sing
just because he enjoys watching people be lifted. He will have a strong
self-identity in all situations.

The negative aspect of the number 7 is that this person will hide out in his
shell - he will just stay in his house a whole lot and he won’t like to come
out. He lives in his shell; he has the ability to grow in that shell and not go
out. His house goes with him, he wants to be totally protected. A 7 can be
easily swayed by other people and unfamiliar surroundings. Seven’s who work
through this block feel at home everywhere.
      </description>
      <karma>
This person is overwhelmed by everything in the external world. He will walk
into an office with a speech all ready but will be unable to speak at all. There
is so much input coming through his aura that it totally confuses his mind. What
this person can hope to gain by doing something about it, is to be able to walk
into any situation and feel totally confident; no matter how much negativity is
present in his surroundings, he will uplift that situation because his aura is
so strong that the negative input will not be able to penetrate his aura.
      </karma>
      <soul>
When this person processes internal information he does not have the ability to
uplift himself; he can’t get his spirit moving. He can’t uplift his own internal
processes so that life would seem good or exciting. Working through this block
will give this person instant ability to uplift his own soul and to connect to
his soul in terms of allowing that expression of the flowing spirit. When he
sits to meditate he will be able to easily channel the constant flow of
uplifting soul energy.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person is always able to uplift situations. He can walk into any situation
and bring spirit into it. This person is the “life of the party.” He can
generate good energy easily.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
People will see a person with a Destiny of 7 as a very uplifting, elevating type
of person.
      </destiny>
      <path>
This person has to learn to be merciful, like Guru Har Rai. He has to learn to
uplift all of humanity, always give inspiration and make people feel hope where
there is no hope. This person can look at a situation and see all the pain
involved, and he will be able to bring the other person out of that
situation. By meditating this person will tune himself into this mercy.

The birthday February l3th, 1954 has a Path Number of 7 (1+3+2+1+9+5+4=7). In
order for a person with this birthday to be fulfilled, he must uplift himself
and others. He must uplift humanity. His position in life is that in order to
feel his most divine self he must uplift. That is what he has to do. Many people
who are into singing have a lot of 7-energy. Many people who are out front in
the Dharma have a lot of 7’s. We have some people who have three or four
7’s. Sat Kirpal Singh has three 7’s; Premka has three 7’s. A person with a 7 is
one who is out front a lot, whose presence is real powerful. The number 7 is a
very powerful number. These people have a real strong presence; they don’ t lose
the sense of who they are. That is because outside influences don’ t throw them
off. Their aura is strong enough that they don't get thrown off.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="8">
      <description>
The Eight Body is the Pranic Body, it represents Guru Har Krishan’s quality of
Purity.

The number 8 also stands for healing. My Path Number is 8 and I am a
Chiropractor. Healing has always been the thing that I loved most, and it is the
thing that gives me the most joy in life. It is written in my astrology
chart. Everything in my chart says “Heal, heal, heal, heal,” everything.

If you master 8 you also master 2, 3, and 4 (“When you master pranayama you will
have control of your mind").

Music can bring automatic mastery of the 8th Body because music takes tremendous
control of prana. Singing will give you tremendous control of your Pranic Body.
The person with an 8 will want to see others really jazzed up in terrns of
energy. An 8 looks to food for energy and tries to get energy from gross forms
rather than from subtle sources.

The negative aspect of the number 8 is being tired all the time. This is the one
thing that doctors have missed: Tiredness does not come from the adrenal
glands. That is the biggest mistake in the medical field. Tiredness comes from
your Pranic Body not working. The Pranic Body is your diaphragm. When you open
up the diaphragm (which is the main exercise you give to somebody who has
adrenal problems), when you get the diaphragm flexed out, the Pranic Body starts
working and there is no more tiredness. Tiredness has nothing to do with
adrenals. The energy to the adrenals comes from the Pranic Body.
      </description>
      <karma>
You will see a lot of fear in this person. No matter what he gets into, there is
never enough energy to do it. He does not have the infinite vision to see that
he can do better. The positive aspect of the number 8 in this position is that
once he harrnonizes the eighth body, he will able to look at a very finite
situation and project outwards. He will be able to see the steps that he has to
take to make it from where he is to where he wants to be. By having mastery of
the Pranic Body he will able to follow through with his plan and make it to his
goal.

Mastery of this body gives one that ability to have the energy to control the
prana to do that which one needs to do and also to gain the vision to be able to
see a more infinite picture of what it is that one is involved in. This person
is the “long-range planner.”
      </karma>
      <soul>
The main blockage that this person has in processing his own internal states is
fear. It is said, “Spiritual people should be happy,” but this person will say,
“Oh... I can’t be happy because....” He will always find some excuse which is
fear-oriented. This fear will keep him from being able to see happiness and joy
in his life. The positive aspect of this number, once he works on this body, is
that he will be totally fearless to deal with anything that comes his way. Once
he tunes in to his soul he will see the expansiveness of his relationship with
God. He will see that he is God, that he is Infinite; he will be in the ecstasy
of the joy of seeing the infinity of God, the Wahe Guru.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person will be fearless. This person is sought after when one wants to
expand a business - get an 8 in your team and ask him, “Where can we go from
here?” This person can plan ahead and help you get ahead.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
The basic viewpoint of this person is that he is fearless and he has the ability
to carry through when everybody else fails by the wayside.He has the ability to
latch unto some project and take it all the way to its maximum.
      </destiny>
      <path>
Guru Har Krishan had so much joy and compassion for his town that he gave up his
life so that all else could live; this is an incredible example of Purity to
follow.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="9">
      <description>
The Ninth Body is the Subtle Body; it gives a person the ability to be
subtle. It is represented by Guru Teg Bahadur and the quality of Calmness. It is
easy for a 9 to tune into what is really happening.

The negative aspect of the number 9 would be to be super-gullible - the
inability to be subtle. This block can make a person innocently naive.
      </description>
      <karma>
A person with a Karma of 9 is not subtle in his external relationships. In
business and emotional relationships he will be very crude; he lacks gentleness
and the beautiful flow that a 9 can have. When the 9 is working one can be as
graceful as the swan. This person might see the negative sides of situations but
he will blur them out; he is innocently naive. If the 9 is working, this person
will see the problem and he will work it out on a subtle level so that the
relationship becomes very smooth. Instead of confronting somebody very directly
this person will let you know that he knows, and offer graceful ways to correct
the problem.

Let’s say you know somebody who has no interest in Kundalini Yoga and he has a 9
in his Karma position. If you ask him, “What do you do for a living?” most
likely he will answer, “Well, I had fifty-seven jobs...” He can’t stick with
anything because his problem is that his Subtle Body is not working.

This particular person’s frustation in life comes from getting a new job every 3
months, and the reason why he gets sick is because he can’t keep a job.

His cure would be to do something over and over again. If he has a hobby he
really likes he should really dive into it. It doesn’t have to be a yogic
technique, but if he practices a yogic technique, great! If not, he can still
work through his karma by just totally diving in. Tell him, “You have to work on
your hobby every day for half an hour.” It will do wonders for him. It’s
incredible! That discipline of working on his hobby will give him mastery. When
he gets mastery he will not go from job to job to job.

I have a 9 for my Karma and this meant that the Virgo in me had to be a master;
I had to take something and master it. You will find that Virgos can be very
one-pointed about doing things, about being very articulate, and about just
getting systems down. The act of mastery gives you the ability to know the
subtle things about your art, your craft, or whatever it is that you are doing.

Michaelangelo was a master. What made him a master was that he lived and
breathed his art. Whatever you do, live it, breathe it and become a master at
it. A master understands the subtlety of the art that he is doing.
      </karma>
      <soul>
In his own relationsbip with himself and his Soul, this person is very hard on
himself; he doesn’t give himself the consciousness to stick to things. He will
not want to master; his misery comes from everything being a mystery; whereas,
his joy comes from mastering things. He will stick with something for a short
period of time but once he will learn to stay with things and have that mastery,
he will become very subtle. This is the artist. This person may be very crude
and hard om himself, but once he does a process to get this particular body in
harmony he will be gentle with himself and give himself a little more space and
time to be the master at any particular thing. The prime example is Guru Teg
Bahadur meditating for 26 years before he became Guru. This number gives one the
ability to be totally at ease, and gives one complete knowledge and mastery of
any situation. It is like the lotus flower on the water, it just rides along and
doesn’t fight the waves.

In the birthday 9/9/1954 one has a Soul which is a 9 and a Gift which is also a
9. What this means is that God gave him as a gift his Soul. These people are
usually very in tune on a very deep level with their own being, so it is not the
Soul they need to work om, but it may be the Path Number that they need to work
on. You can give them any meditation, and if they do it for 1000 days it will
automatically work on the Subtle Body.
      </soul>
      <gift>
This person can master situations very quickly. He is very accurate about what
goes on around him.

A birthday in the year 1954 has a Gift Number of 9. This person’s gift is that
he is master. Whatever he tries to do, he’ll understand the subtlety of it very
quickly.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
People will see this person as being very masterful. He learns systems and
learns things very quickly.
      </destiny>
      <path>
What this person has to manifest in terms of his Path is that he has to be very
masterful and has to exhibit total calmness in whatever it is that he does. This
brings about the subtlety of things. He never gets excited about anything; not
that he is dull, but he can process information in such a way that it soothes
people. By doing a meditation for 1000 days this person will gain the ability to
express his own spirituality with subtlety and calmness.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="10">
      <description>
Every number is reduced to a one digit number except the numbers 10 and 11. The
Tenth Body is the Radiant Body. The Royal Courage of Guru Gobind Singh is the
divine expression of this body.

People who have the number 10 working for them walk into a room and everybody
notices them. People who have no radiance and no spark look like death warmed
over - they have a 10 that doesn’t work. The perfect definition of a 10 that’s
not working is “banana spine”.

People with a 10 should keep their hair long, do the Archer Pose, and drink cucumber juice.      
      </description>
      <karma>
This person will be “All or Nothing,” and usually he will be very “banana spine”
in his relationships and business dealings. The positive aspect of this position
is manifested as radiance in his involvements, both business and emotional. He
will put 150% effort into his work.
      </karma>
      <soul>
This person’ s attitude is, “I can’t do it; I don’t have the energy; Oh, God,
I’m just not able to...” The world for this person is “nothing”; he can never
make things happen. What a person can hope to get out of a meditation is the
attitude of, “I’m going to give it my 150%,” no matter what it is that he will
do. If he is going to meditate, he will sit down and do it with 150% of his
energy.
      </soul>
      <gift>
If you own a company and you want something to happen, ask a person with a 10 as
a Gift to get involved and he will make things happen, quicker than anybody
else. He does his work with such zest that the project itself will manifest
radiance. Whatever this person applies himself to becomes radiant.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
This person is seen as being very radiant and as doing everything with a lot of
zest and energy.
      </destiny>
      <path>
Royal Courage is the perfect definition of what this person has to manifest in
his lifetime.

In the birthday 9/9/l954 the numbers are: Soul number=9, Karma number =9, Gift
number =9, Destiny number =10 and the Path number=10

A Destiny (Century) number of 10 means that this person worked on his Radiant
Body many times in his past lifetimes. With a Path Number of 10 the key is to do
a meditation like “Gobinde Mukande Udare Apare Hariang Kariang Nirname Akame,”
the mantra that Guru Gobind Singh gave us. If he meditates on this mantra for
1000 days, it will not only take care of his Soul, but it will also take care of
his Path. In a 1000-day period, it can turn that being totally around.
      </path>
    </number>
    <number value="11">
      <description>
Every number is reduced to a one digit number except the numbers 10 and 11. If
you have an 11 in any position, do not change it. Thus, whenever you have an 11
in your numerology, it does not turn into a 2. For example, let’s take December
the l3th - the 12 of the month would change into 3 and the 13 would change into
a 4, but with October the 11th, nor the 10 does not change neither the 11, leave
it as an 11.

The number 11 represents the Siri Guru Granth, the “Entirety,” the “Perfection
of the Being.”

The numbers for somebody with a birthday on November 11, 1947, are 11, 11,
11. This rneans that this person has to have a very intense relationship with
the Guru.  When you bow before the Siri Guru Granth your Arc Line merges with
the Arc Line of the Guru’s feet and your 10 bodies automatically work perfectly;
that is why the most important discipline, the most valuable discipline for a
Yoga student is to go before the Guru and bow, because it automatically makes
the 10 bodies work.

People who have 11 in key numbers must spend a lot of time with the Guru -
serving the Guru, Parkash, whathever - they have to put a lot into the Guru. It
is amazing how many people have 11’s. I know one lady that has 3 11’s, and she
is a holy terror. Now she is finally responding to that and it totally switched
her. She has an 11 in the Gift position, but she has been resisting that
gift. She didn’t accept gifts very easily.

The number 11 is a Scorpio (in Astrology). A negative 11 would be really down
into the Scorpio consciousness. There are 3 aspects of Scorpio: the Scorpion,
the Eagle, and the Phoenix. The Siri Guru Granth is like the Phoenix - that pure
light, this is the positive aspect. The negative of this number is the real
scorpion projective consciousness. A person with an 11 in a negative position
can forget his infinity and be ruled by Maya.
      </description>
      <karma>
A Karma of 11 means that the Karma is set.

An 11 in this position represents mastery of the physical realm. In a negative
sense, this person has no mastery of the physical realm; he is always worried
about money and about his physical looks - he wants the prettiest cars and he is
always concerned about how others see hirn. In a positive sense this person is
elegant, royal and divine, and he knows it, so he wears the best clothes and he
drives the nicest car, but not because of what others might think of him, but
because he has the highest opinion of himself.
      </karma>
      <soul>
This person will have a huge conflict because he wants to be the complete master
of himself and he can’t see at all how he can do it. The only way he can become
a master is to surrender to the Guru. Once he surrenders to the Guru (and I
recommend raading from the Guru for 1000 days) he will allow God to run his life
and he will know that God is really the Master. Then he becomes the
representative of God and he becomes master of the physical universe; therefore
money doesn’t bug him and nothing bothers him.
      </soul>
      <gift>
A person with a Gift of 11 is able to express the energy of any one of the
spiritual bodies whenever he needs to.
      </gift>
      <destiny>
The number 11 is called “Unchangeable Destiny.” It is written: There is no
change - your destiny is written, it has been written and will never change.
This person is looked at as someone who constantly reminds people of God,
through his dress, through his projection, or in any other way he will remind
other people of Infinity.
      </destiny>
      <path>
This person must become the Siri Guru. He must become a constant reminder of God
to other people. The way he can do this is by bringing other people to the Feet
of the Guru - the Siri Guru Granth. Whenever he is having a conversation he can
always take that person and expand that person’s consciousness through that
interchange; he can expand other people to Infinity. People walk away from this
person feeling very elevated and very conscious.
      </path>
    </number>
  </numbers>

  <notes>
    <note title="soul and gift are 3">
If the Soul Number is a 3 and the Gift is a 3, it means that this person has the
ability to know his Soul; it means that he has the ability to connect to his
Soul when he wants to. His Gift is mastery of the 3rd Body and in order to
connect with his Soul he has to master the 3rd Body, but it has already been
given to him as a Gift, so he doesn’t have to. Having a 3 both as Soul and as
Gift means that this person has the ability to connect to his Soul already. It
means that as a child he was able to connect with his Soul readily. There are a
lot of people in 3H0 that are like that.
    </note>
    <note title="soul and gift are the same">
If your Gift is the same number as your Soul, it means that you have been given
as a Gift, mastery of that particular body which allows you to communicate with
your Soul freely. It is like a freeway - once you connect with that freeway and
make that map, you can always go back and forth. If you are given that as a
gift, it means that you have the ability to travel back and forth between your
earthly and spiritual consciousness very easily, however, sometimes it can make
you lazy...
    </note>
  </notes>
</information>
